fnhc.ca 2018-09-30

# First Nations Health Council | Privacy Statement - First Nations Health Council

**Our Commitment**

We are committed to protecting your privacy while you are visiting our website for information. The First Nations Health Council (“FNHC”) and our website is governed by the BC [ _Personal Information Protection Act_  ](http://www.bclaws.ca/EPLibraries/bclaws_new/document/ID/freeside/00_03063_01). If you choose not to use the Internet to provide your personal information to FNHC, you contact by telephone, fax, mail or in person. (Not all options may be available in every situation.)

**Scope**

This privacy statement describes the information we collect via the FNHC website and social media accounts, along with how we collect and use that information. We reserve the right to update this statement at any time. Users are responsible for reviewing this document periodically for changes.

**Personal Information**

Personal information is recorded information about an identifiable individual. Personal information includes things such as an individual’s name, address, birth date, e-mail address, phone number, identifying number, health care history and education history.

**Collection**

Personal information is collected via this website and social media in certain circumstances, such as when you send an email message to us or complete a questionnaire, form, or other on-line survey found on our website. When you send us electronic mail, we collect your email address, your IP address and your message so that we may reply to you. We recommend that sensitive personal information not be sent unencrypted over the Internet or by e-mail.

When you visit our website, the web server collects a small amount of information to facilitate the operation and security of our website. This information may include browser type, Internet domain name and IP address. Some information, such as your Internet domain name or IP address, may identify you. This information is not accessed by anyone outside the FNHC.

The website search function collects information to remember the information you submitted for the search. We do not collect personal information such as your name, or home address while you visit and use our website.

Information provided by you becomes a record of the organization and is subject to the access and privacy protection requirements set out in the BC  _Personal Information Protection Act_. This information may be further collected, used and disclosed in accordance with  _PIPA_  or as otherwise required by law. Under this legislation you are entitled to access and correct any of your personal information that is within our custody and control. You may make such requests by contacting the privacy representative listed below.

**Use**

The FNHC may use and share your information for the following purposes:

  * To identify and communicate with you;
  * For your immediate and ongoing health care;
  * To help improve First Nations quality of care and services;
  * For research purposes, if authorized and permitted by law;

To understand your eligibility for benefits and services and to arrange payment;

The FNHC only uses the personal information collected from the website for the same purpose that it was collected.   The FNHC will not use your personal information for another purpose without your consent.

**Sharing**

The FNHC may only disclose your personal information if it is done for the same purpose that it was collected.  The FNHC will not share your personal information for another purpose unless the FNHC has your consent to do so.  In limited circumstances, and only where clearly permitted under  _PIPA_ , the FNHC may be required, or authorized, by law to disclose your personal information to another party.

**Links**

Our website contains links to other sites. When clicking on a link, we encourage you to examine the site’s privacy statement and make your own decision regarding the information provided.

**Social buttons**

There may be “social buttons” on some FNHC pages for sharing items through social networking websites. Social buttons let visitors share or bookmark web pages, and are often identifiable by the + sign with Share beside it. In order to connect social buttons to the relevant external sites, there are scripts from those domains, which are outside of this site. Those sites could be collecting information about what you are doing all around the internet, including this site. To be certain what information those sites collect and how to opt out, check the respective policies of each site.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a small file containing certain pieces of information that a website creates when you visit the site. It can track how and when you use a site, which site you visited immediately before, and it can store that information about you. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer.  There are two types of cookies, session cookies and persistent cookies: our website uses both of these to improve your website experience and to arrange content according to your interests and viewing preferences. Cookies also help us understand traffic patterns so that we can improve site navigation. Cookies cannot be used by themselves to identify you and do not hold or track any personal information about you.

If you have concerns about the use of cookies, you can change your web browser to not accept this information or display warning messages. However, you may not be able to use all the interactive features on our website if cookies are disabled. Because each browser is different, check the “Help” menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.

**Web statistics**

First Nations Health Council uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses first-party cookies to track visitor interactions. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of this website, compiling reports on website activity for the website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf.

FNHC uses IP masking within Google Analytics to anonymize personal information collected by Google. IP masking is a customization which removes the last octet of the visitor’s IP address prior to its use and storage by Google. This IP information is not viewable by FNHA.

Website visitors who do not want to be tracked by Google Analytics can download the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on. The add-on communicates with the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js) to indicate that information about the website visit should not be sent to Google Analytics. The Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on does not prevent information from being sent to the website itself or to other web analytics services.

For more information visit the Google Analytics Overview page.  
**Questions and Complaints**

If you have a question or concern about any collection, use or disclosure of personal information by FNHC, FNHA or the FNHDA, or about a request for access to your own personal information, please contact Privacy Office:

First Nations Health Authority  
FNHA Privacy Office  
#320, 757 W. Hastings St.

Vancouver, BC, V6C 1A1  
Tel: 604-693-6844  
Toll-free 1-844-364-7748  
Email: [privacy@fnha.ca](mailto:privacy@fnha.ca)

If you are not satisfied with the response you receive, you should contact the Information and Privacy Commissioner of British Columbia:

The Office of the Information and Privacy Commissioner  
O. Box 9038, Stn Prov Govt  
Victoria, BC  V8W 9A4

Tel:  1-800-663-7867 or 250-387-5629  
Fax:  250-387-1696  
Email:  [info@oipc.bc.ca](mailto:info@oipc.bc.ca)  
Website: [http://www.oipc.bc.ca](http://www.oipc.bc.ca/)
